

CONTACT ME AT

- wendellchansuazo11@gmail.com
- 09959768531
- <u>https://wendell1101.github.io/</u>
- https://www.linkedin.com/in/wendell-suazo-8339251aa/
- blk. 26 Lot 17, GK Village, Majada In, Canlubang, Calamba City, Laguna

SKILLS SUMMARY

- •••• Software Development
- •••• HTML, CSS, SASS, Bootstrap, Tailwind
- •••• Javascript, Jquery, AJAX, Vue JS
- •••• PHP, Laravel, MYSQL, GIT, Github

AWARDS RECEIVED

- President Lister Polytechnic University of the Philippines Oct 2019 - March 2022
- Computer Specialist of the Year Majada In Integrated School
 Mar 2016
- Class Valedictorian Majada In Elementary School 2009 - 2010 Grade 4 – Grade 6
- First Honor Majada In Elementary School 2008 - 2010 Grade 4 - Grade 6
- First Honor San Cristobal Elementary School 2005 - 2007 Grade 2 – Grade 3

WENDELL SUAZO

BACKEND DEVELOPER

PROFILE SUMMARY

Experienced Full Stack Web Developer with a demonstrated history of working in personal and business services industry. Skilled in Frontend and Backend Development . Strong engineering professional with a Bachelor of Science - BS focused in Information Technology from Polytechnic University of the Philippines.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Freelance Web-Developer

Jan. 2021- present

• Create web applications for clients depending on their needs for personal and business use.

Software Developer

Blue Aurora Solutions Inc. | June 2022- present

- Managed Frontend and Backend development using Laravel and Vue JS
- Created API endpoints for frontend to consume(Web and Mobile) REST APIs and Graphql
- Able to implement payment methods such as Shopeepay and Lalamove for three different countries(Philippines, Thailand, Vietnam)
- Making fixes and adjustment for existing payment methods such as Paypal, GCASH and GRAB PAY, VNPAY, zalopay, eghl for Mobile API endpoints
- Collaborated with other developers
- Created stand-alone multitenancy projects:
 - Attendance System for employees during campaigns
 - Assembly web app
 - Riders portal

Full Stack Web Developer Intern

Blue Aurora Solutions Inc. | March 2022- May. 2022

- Full stack development using Laravel and Vue JS
- Created API endpoints for frontend to consume
- Collaborated with other developers

Backend Developer

IThinkWeb Corporation | July 2021- Jan. 2022

- Managed complex projects from start to finish
- Created API endpoints for frontend to consume
- Collaborated with other developers

NOTABLE PROJECTS

FLOWERSTORE ATTENDANCE SYSTEM

Built a complete attendance system for flowerstore.ph employees. Features:

- Time in, Time out
- Mass upload of employee
- Mass Generate Payslip
- Mass Print of Employee IDs
- Email notification of payslips and attendance

CALAMBA ENTREP ONLINE STORE

Calamba Entrep is an online marketplace where anyone can sell, buy, and discover one-of-a-kind products. We stand behind our merchants & their products. We're also a community working to make a difference for small businesses.

Technology used: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Javascript, PHP, MYSQL, Laravel, Laravel-livewire, Vue Js

■ TECH2U COMPUTER REPAIR SERVICE

Tech2U Computer Repair Service is a place for you to to fix your computers and cellphone gadgets at affordable and reasonable price. We've been repairing broken or corrupted electronic gadgets. Whether your device fell on concrete or water, we'll make sure it will run again in its best condition.

Technology used: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Javascript, PHP/Laravel, Laravel-livewire, MYSQL

■ ENRICO MERCHANDISE

An Eccommerce Web application made mainly using Laravel 7 as server-side language. The customer has the ability to add to cart the selected items, checkout and pay using Cash on Delivery(COD) or through PAYPAL. The system also offers complete administration panel and users are divided into several roles/privelages such as admin, product manager and customer.

Technology used: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Javascript, PHP/Laravel, MYSQL

EDUCATION

Polytechnic University of the Philippines
 Bachelor of Science in Information Technology
 2018 - 2022

STI College Calamba
 IT and Mobile App Development, Information Technology
 2016 – 2018

- Graduated senior high school in STI College Calamba with Technical Vocational strand specializing in IT and Mobile App Development
- Majada In Integrated School

2012 - 2016

Junior High School

• Majada In Elementary School

2008 – 2012 Elementary School

• San Cristobal Elementary School

2004 - 2008

Elementary School